# **CLAUDIA MARTÍN**

## Front End Developer

Palma, Spain cmartin.office@gmail.com +34 634 492 018 in/claudia-martin-office

Front End Developer with +4 years of experience, passionate about continuous learning and creating sustainable code. I enjoy collaborating in teams, facing logical challenges to design attractive and functional interfaces that make the difference.

JavaScript TypeScript

React

Git

CSS

CSS Preprocessors

HTML

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

eDreams ODIGEO

Palma, Spain (Hybrid)

Apr. 2023 - Oct. 2023

Front End Developer

- Contributed to the development of own products using collaborative and management tools such as Jira, Confluence, GitLab, Slack, Lucid and Google Meet.
- Participated in **Kanban methodology** ceremonies, such as dailies, task replenishments, refinements and retrospectives, encouraging communication, feedback and the continuous improvement of the team.
- Ensured code quality through best practices, implementing esLint, tests with Jest, pair programming and code reviews in GitLab, mainly TypeScript code in React applications.
- I played a key role in the Front End area as Prime Keeper, working on initiatives to increase eDreams Prime user retention.
- Guided and accompanied junior profiles in the resolution of tasks, encouraging their autonomy and ensuring the quality of the work delivered.

**Polarier** Palma, Spain

Software Developer

Nov. 2022 - Mar. 2023

- Led the migration of the main project of management and control of laundry operations, customers and deliveries, providing a more solid and scalable base.
- Redesigned the application and, together with the technical leader, defined a new front end architecture based on components with React, Redux, Tailwind, Material UI, and Materio TPL.
- Started the development of the new project using **SVN** for version control, **node.js** for initialization and webpack for file optimization.
- Migrated and optimized more than 30% of the project, solving performance and maintenance issues of the legacy system.
- Discarded unnecessary dependencies, created a more readable and efficient code structure, reduced technical debt and facilitated future upgrades.
- Also promoted the use of Agile methods in the company, introducing ceremonies and tools such as Click Up.

**APSL** Palma, Spain (Hybrid) Frontend Engineer 2 Jan. 2022 - Aug. 2022 Jan. 2021 - Jan. 2022 Programadora Junior

- Actively participated in scrum ceremonies, facilitating communication, alignment and continuous improvement by presenting ideas, solutions and updates.
- Implemented new features, fixed bugs and made improvements with Full Stack technologies: Django (Python), Pytest, SQL, Vue, Angular, React, RxJS, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SASS and LESS, and Tailwind.

- Progressively focused my work in the Front End area, reaching the **Front End Engineer 2** level in one year.
- Collaborated in a team doing pair programming, reviewing pull requests (GitLab and Bitbucket) and supporting my colleagues with tools like Zulip, Redmine and Google Meet.
- Took care of code quality by applying SOLID and TDD principles.
- Attended meetings with clients to discuss and clarify doubts about the projects under development, ensuring a workflow aligned with their expectations.
- I was a speaker in one of the monthly Tech Talks, contributing to knowledge sharing in the company.
- **Mentored new team members**, helping them to understand the structure of the projects, complete their first tasks successfully and adapt to the work environment.

#### **KUMO** Consultoría

Palma, Spain (Hybrid)

Programadora

Mar. 2019 - Dec. 2020

- Implemented, corrected and improved functionalities in the **Front End** area using **Angular**, **LESS**, **HTML**, **CSS** and **JavaScript**.
- Worked in Back End with the MVC Struts (Java) framework, managing requests and responses, form validation, XML configuration and the integration of Java (Servlets, JDBC) and Front End (JSP, jQuery, CSS) technologies; also with SQL.
- Performed server maintenance tasks and deployments with Apache Tomcat.
- **Designed and maintained landing pages**, as well as made **updates and improvements** in the company's **back office**.
- Used collaborative tools such as Jira, Trello, GitLab, Slack and Google Workspace.
- Actively participated in **gile ceremonies** such as dailies, retrospectives and client meetings, fostering an **iterative approach and focused on user needs**.
- Led with the CEO the development of a project with Django (Python) and Vue, managing from planning to delivery of the MVP.
- Demonstrated **adaptability** in remote work and training, **maintaining and even improving my productivity levels in COVID-19 times**.

#### **EDUCATION**

CFGS en Desarrollo de Aplicaciones Web (Dual)

Palma, Spain

CIFP Francesc de Borja Moll

2020

Bachillerato en la modalidad de ciencias

Palma, Spain

IES Son Rullan

2015

### **LANGUAGES**

#### **English**

First Certificate (Cambridge University)

#### **Spanish**

Native

#### Catalan

Native